ADEMIR ROCHA

CONTACT

E-mail: aamr.eco@gmail.com Website: www.aderocha.com

PROFILE

Ademir Rocha received his Ph.D. in Economic Theory from the University of São Paulo in 2022. He is a Lecturer at the Department of Economics at the University of São Paulo and Researcher at The Institute of Economic Research Foundation (Fipe). His research focuses on large-scale modeling, with particular interest in environmental economics and regional and urban economics topics.

EDUCATION

- Ph.D. in Economic Theory, University of São Paulo	2018-2022
Ph.D. Thesis: Climate change, water resources and economic impacts: An analysis	s of
Brazilian hydrographic regions (Supervisor: Prof. Eduardo Haddad)	
- M.Sc. in Applied Economics	2016-2017
- BA in Economics	2012-2015

EXPERIENCE

Economic Consultant, The Institute of Economic Research Foundation - Fipe	2020 - Present
Lecturer, Department of Economics, University of São Paulo	
Grade: Macroeconomics Introduction - National Accounting	2022 - Present
Lecturer, Department of Economics, University of São Paulo	
Grade: Microeconomics Introduction	2022 - Present
Assistant Professor, Department of Economics, University of São Paulo	
Grade: Applied General Equilibrium Models I and II	2019 - Present

RESEARCH FIELD

- Input-Output and CGE Analysis
- Environmental Economics
- Climate Change Economics
- Regional and Urban Economics

PUBLICATION LIST

- Water charge and natural areas conservation: An ex-ante assessment of a policy proposal	
for the Mantiqueira region, Brazil, Water Resources Research.	2023
- New economy for the Brazilian Amazon, WRI Report.	2023
- The geography of manufacturing productivity shocks in Colombia The Colombian Economy	
and Its Regional Structural Challenges (Book Chapter), The Colombian Economy	
and Its Regional Structural Challenges. Advances in Spatial Science. Springer.	2023
- Input-output analysis of the Ukraine war: A tool for assessing the internal territorial	
impacts of the conflict, Regional Science Policy & Practice.	2022
- The key to knowledge: Evaluating the role of gatekeepers on regional inventive performance,	
Journal of Technology Transfer.	2022
- The New Economic Geography and labour emigration: Analysing Venezuela's hyperinflation	
episode, Journal of International Development.	2021
- A bad year? Climate variability and the wine industry in Chile, Wine Economics and	
Policy.	2020
- Spatial distribution of logistics services in Brazil: A potential market analysis, Regional	
Science Policy & Practice.	2020
- Agricultural technology adoption and land use: evidence for Brazilian municipalities,	
Journal of Land Use Science.	2019
- Modelling the location choice: evidence from an evolutionary game based on regional	
input-output analysis, Regional Studies.	2019
WORKING IN PROGRESS	
- Economic impacts of floods in Santiago, Chile.	2024
- Assessing the economic and water-related impacts of desalination plants in Chile	-0-1
using an interregional computable general equilibrium model.	2024
- What is the economic value of illegal deforestation?	2023
- Domestic trade drives Brazilian Amazon's deforestation.	2023
- Region-specific carbon footprints of Brazilian products.	2023
- Virtual carbon by emission source: an analysis of the Brazilian case.	2023
- Economic evaluation of the Croatian Community Water System Investment	
Program 2021-2030: an ex-ante analysis with CGE model.	2022
- Climate change, water resources and economic impacts in Brazilian hydrographic regions.	2022
- Measuring the causal effect of no-till system adoption on Brazilian natural areas.	2021
y manger and a second s	

LANGUAGES

- Portuguese (Native)
- English (Intermediate)

SKILLS

- R (Advanced)
- Python/QGIS (Advanced)
- Matlab (Advanced)
- Stata (Intermediate)